mara.gov.au 2018-08-15

# Privacy Policy - Office of the Migration Agents Registration Authority

This privacy policy applies to personal information collected by the Office of the Migration Agents Registration OMARA (the “OMARA”). The OMARA is bound by provisions relating to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information by various Commonwealth laws – particularly the _Migration Act 1958_ (Cth) (the “Migration Act”) and the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) (the “Privacy Act”).

This privacy policy is an overview, and does not provide details about all of the OMARA’s personal information management practices, procedures and systems. Further information can be obtained from the Department of Home Affairs (the Department) privacy policy at the Department’s webpage.   
[Department of Home Affairs Privacy Policy  
](http://www.immi.gov.au/pub-res/Pages/policy/privacy-policy.aspx "DIBP Privacy Policy")

### The OMARA’s role

The key objectives of the OMARA are to ensure that:

  * consumers understand their rights and agents understand their obligations under the regulatory framework;
  * only suitable persons are registered as migration agents, and unsuitable persons are refused registration or re-registration;
  * registered migration agents maintain appropriate knowledge and skills to enable them to provide accurate and timely advice to consumers;
  * registered migration agents are monitored to ensure the integrity of their conduct and the quality of the immigration assistance provided to consumers; and
  * consumers of the services of registered, or formerly registered, migration agents are provided with an efficient and effective complaints handling service.

### The OMARA’s obligations under the Privacy Act

This privacy policy sets out how we comply with our obligations under the _Privacy Act 1988_.  The Privacy Act sets out 13 Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) that regulate the collection, use, disclosure and storage of personal information and how individuals can access and correct personal information held about them.  The OMARA is legally bound by the APPs.

The Privacy Act defines ‘personal information’ as:

information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:

(a)  whether the information or opinion is true or not; and

(b)  whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.

The Privacy Act also places a higher standard of protection on sensitive information.  Sensitive information includes:

Information or an opinion about an individual's:

  * racial or ethnic origin
  * political opinions
  * membership of a political association
  * religious beliefs or affiliations
  * philosophical beliefs
  * membership of a professional or trade association
  * membership of a trade union
  * sexual orientation or practices
  * criminal record
  * health information about an individual
  * genetic information about an individual that is not otherwise health information
  * biometric information that is to be used for the purpose of automated biometric verification or biometric identification
  * biometric templates

Show All
